Guide to the Herbert Isaac Winer Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1911-2014; Accessions 2018-M-0001, 2018-M-0004; 20.52; (48 boxes)
  - Yale University files, 1940s-2004
    - Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
      - Administrative records
        - Reports, 1983–1988 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Report to Committee on Accretitation of the Society of American Foresters, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Rosters of faculty and staff, 1988–1989 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - Safety committee, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Salmon Brook Associates resource management course, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - School forests, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - School policy, 1953–1961 (Box 28, Folder 1)
        - Self evaluation, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Shield design, 1993–1994 (Box 28, Folder 3)
        - Strategic Advisory Council, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 4)
        - Student Assistant Procedure, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 5)
        - Student handbooks, 1987–1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Tropical Resources Institute, 1988–1989 (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - Two-year Program files, 1959–1960 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Vegetation Measurement Module and manuel, 1994–1995 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Yale Library science journals, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Yale Reports radio program, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Course files
        - 120 exams, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - 173 outlines, 1954–1955 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - 173 outlines, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - 173b Analysis of Logging Operations files, 1952–1964 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
        - 700b files, 1994–1995 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - 723b syllabus, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - 725 syllabus, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - 726a files, 1988–1994 (Box 29, Folder 9-10)
        - 726a files, 1988–1994 (Box 30, Folder 1-5)
        - 726a files, 1988–1994 (Box 31, Folder 1-6)
        - 726a files, 1988–1994 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        - 727b files, 1992–1996 (Box 32, Folder 2-7)
        - 727b files, 1992–1996 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
        - 729a files, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 3)
        - 736a files, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
        - Advanced Logging Cost Analysis seminar, 1961–1962 (Box 33, Folder 5)
        - Course materials from other professors, 1970s-1980s (Box 33, Folder 6)
        - Ecosystem Measurement Module, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 7)
        - Hull Forest Products class visit, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 8)
        - Logging and Grades course materials, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
        - Logging and Grades course materials, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
      - Field files
        - Bogalusa, Louisiana, Gaylord Container Division, circa 1960s (Box 34, Folder 3)
        - Crossett, Arkansas
          - A&M field day, 1950–1958 (Box 34, Folder 4)
          - Camp affairs, 1954–1973 (Box 34, Folder 5-7)
          - Centennial celebration, 1962–1999 (Box 34, Folder 8)
          - Crossett logging studies, 1956–1965 (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
          - Crossett Lumber Company and city material, 1953–1985 (Box 35, Folder 3)
          - Corssett News Observer files, circa 1960s (Box 35, Folder 4)
          - Forest management instructional manuel, 1954–1964 (Box 35, Folder 5)
          - Presbyterian Church of Crossett, 1958–1965 (Box 35, Folder 6)
          - Publications, 1948–1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
          - Report on Crossett Lumber Company, 1912 (Box 36, Folder 2)
          - Sale to Georgia-Pacific Corporation, 1960–1963 (Box 36, Folder 3)
          - Sawmill reports and papers on wood-using plants, 1949 (Box 36, Folder 4)
          - Student food surveys, 1992–1993 (Box 36, Folder 5)
          - Thank you notes, 1991–1993 (Box 36, Folder 6)
          - Trip schedule, 1995–1996 (Box 36, Folder 7)
          - Yale site, 1911–1914 (Box 36, Folder 8)
        - El Dorado, Arkansas, Reynolds and Draper Lumber Company, 1955–1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - Fordyce, Arkansas, Fordyce Lumber Company, 1952–1965 (Box 37, Folder 2)
        - Hamburg, Arkansas, Tommy Reynolds Lumber Company, 1963–1964 (Box 37, Folder 3)
        - Portland, Oregon, International Woodworkers, 1957–1963 (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - Prescott, Arkansas, Ozan Lumber Company, 1955–1967 (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
        - Warren, Arkansas, Potlatch Forests Incorporated, 1952–1967 (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
        - White Mountain National Forest, 1986–1996 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Student files
        - Academic Standing Reports, 1953–1962 (Box 38, Folder 1)
        - Advisee files, 1992–1993 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
        - Student material, 1953-2001 (Box 38, Folder 4-17)
        - Student material, 1953-2001 (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
    - Yale general
      Yale University related files are restricted until 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yaleuniversity- archives
      - Admissions, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Black Panther trial report, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Rights and responsibilities, 1950s (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Sterling Fellowship, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Yale University Library Committee, 1954–1958 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Personal and post-retirement files, 1937–2014
    - Blackwell, Lloyd F., 1937 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - California memorabilia, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Clippings on Yale and forestry, 1970s-1990s (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
    - Connecticut forestry workshop, 2003 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Forest Resources Association bulletin, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Judaism files, 1960s-1990s (Box 40, Folder 7-9)
    - New York Times correspondence, 1952–2002 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, 1960s-1990s (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence, William O. Douglas, 1963 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Post-retirement correspondence
      - Armstrong, Frank, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - Babbitt, Bruce, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Bentley, William, 1997–2005 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - Berlyn, Graeme, 2012 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Berlyn, Robin, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Beslau, Jonathan, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Chun, Marvin, 2012 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Coppock, Jane, 1996–1997 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Cronon, William, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Cushing, Barbara, 2012–2015 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Darling, O.H., 1999 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Fickle, Jim, 2010–2013 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Fordyce, David, 1996–1999 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Furnival, George M., 1997 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Gordon, John C., 1998 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Heidersdorf, Ernie, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Larson, Bruce C., 1996–2002 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Laverdiere, Michel, 2005–2014 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Levin, Richard, 1999–2002 (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - McLoughlin, John, 2004 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Newson, H.P., 1998 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Okrascewski, James D., 1996 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Oliver, Chad, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Robinson, Fred C., 1997 (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Russ, Darrell, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 22)
      - Sahlman, Bruce, 2000 (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - Smith, David M., 1996–2009 (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - Sundberg, Ulf, 1997–1998 (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - Ticknor III, William D., 1996 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - Weetman, Gordon, 1996–2000 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - Winer, Hannah, 2006–2007 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - School of Forestry and Environmental Studies files, 2006–2007 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Servis Recorder Charts, circa 1950s (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Society of the Sigma XI Yale Chapter, 1949 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Yale 1942 class files, 1992–1996 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Yale 1942 class files, 1992–1996 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Yale 1942 memorial service, 2007 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Yale 1949 class files, 1995–2005 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Yale 1949 class reunion, 1992–1996 (Box 42, Folder 4-5)
    - Yale Alumni Fund, 1976–1979 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Yale Alumni Magazine, 2011–2012 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Yale Distinguished Alumnus Citation, 2004 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Photographs and slides, 1949–1998
    - Photographs
      - Forest Research Institute of Canada, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Fourth Annual Seminar for Forestry Professors, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada, LRD staff, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Tree photograph and description, circa 1950s (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Crossett, Arkansas
        - En route to camp, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 5)
        - Field day, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - Logging, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 7)
        - Logging and sawmilling, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 8-9)
        - Logging, forest management, milling, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 10)
        - Perc Wilson photographs, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 11)
        - Peter Arnold photographs, Crossett and Norfolk, Arkansas, 1949–1951 (Box 43, Folder 12)
        - Sterling White Logging, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 13)
        - Various photographs, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 14)
        - Walter Meyer photographs, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 15)
        - Yale Camp photographs, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Yale events, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 17-18)
      - Yale events, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 19-21)
      - Yale events, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
      - Yale events, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 3-4)
      - Yale events, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
      - Yale events, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
      - Yale events, 1990s (Box 44, Folder 9-10)
    - Slides
      - Forestry slides, 1960s (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Forestry slides, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Forestry slides, 1972–1973 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Forestry slides, 1990s (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Forestry slides, 1970s-1990s (Box 45, Folder 5-10)
      - Forestry slides, 1970s-1990s (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
      - Shelf list of 35mm Kodachrome slides, circa 1950s (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1927-2011; Accession 2018-M-0039; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  Includes accession 2018-M-0039 and consists of material related to Herbert Winer's studies and teaching at the Yale Forestry School (later Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies), including class notes, lecture notes, administrative files, and material on logging practices gathered from tours of western logging companies in the 1950s. Also includes personal and professional correspondence, and subject and research files from institutions outside of Yale.
  The material is divided into three groupings: correspondence, subject files, and Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies files.
  - Correspondence
    - Barres, Herster, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chapman, Alberta, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Clark, Janice, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Cohen-Anisfeld, Shimon, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Day, Lynn, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Dickenson, Fred E., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Forest Science, 1964–1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Francis, David R., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Koroleff, A.M., 1927–1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Joe, 1997–1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Nylta Club, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Rawson, Claude, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Rogers, George, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Silversides, C. Ross, 1979–1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Smith, Catherine (Bobby), 2010–2011 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Smith, David M., 1968–1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Smith, Fred, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Solomon, Peter J., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Straiton, Paul, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Swan, Stewart, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Ticknor, William D., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Verner, Mary, 1991–1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Winer, David, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Subject files
    - Forest History Society, 1970–1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - L.O. Wright Company Logging, 1981–1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Map- Ed's Story, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Michigan-California Lumber Company, Camino, California, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Pulp and Paper Research Institute of Canada publications, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - University of California, Berkeley publications, 1955–1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies
    - Administrative records
      Yale University related files are restricted until 2039 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. http://web.library.yale.edu/mssa/collections/research-use-of-yale-university-archives
      - Administrative general files, 1948–1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Berkeley College fellowship, 1989–2005 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Centennial history project, 1996–2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Course files
      - Class notes
        - Fall and spring terms, 1947–1948 (Box 1, Folder 30)
          Includes courses 111a: Dendrology; 120a: Soils and Soils Lab; 122a: Silvics; 143a: Improvements; 151a: Mensuration; 160a: Wood Anatomy; 180a: Economics
        - Fall and spring terms, 1947–1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Spring term, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
          Includes courses 121b: Soils Seminar; 124b: Silviculture; 130b: Protection; 126b: Ecology; 131b: Entomology; 156b: Range Management; 169b: Utilization II; 181b: Policy
        - Fall term, 1948–1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
          Includes courses 110a: Forest Pathology; 125a: Silviculture; 149a: Photogrammetry; 152a: Forest Finance; 153:a Management; 170: Logging and Lumber
        - Fall and spring terms, 1949–1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
          Includes courses 183: Statistical methods for W.H. Meyer; Biom 157b for M.H. Quenouille
      - Course 727b, Arkansas itenerary, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Course evaluations and student material, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Lecture notes, Circa 1950s-1960s (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Photographs, Circa 1990s (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Spring field trip, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Western tour
      - Boise Payette Lumber Company, Boise, Idaho, 1954–1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Collins Pine Company, Chester, California, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Diamond Gardner Corporation, Red Bluff, California, 1959–1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Diamond Match Company, Chico, California, 1956–1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Hollow Tree Lumber Company, Ukiah, California, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Homestake Mining Company, Spearfish, South Dakota, 1957–1960 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - J. Neils Lumber Company, Libby, Montana, 1951–1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Log and Expenses, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Masonite Corporation, Ukiah, California, 1953–1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Potlatch Forests Inc., Lewiston, Idaho, 1957–1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - University of Idaho, Moscow, Idaho, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 14)